export default Dpe10 = [
    {
        question: "1. The effective length of the magnet",
        options: ["The distance between the two poles of the magnet",
            "The square of the length of the magnet",
            "The complete length of the magnet",
            "The half of the length of the magnet"],
        correct_option: "The distance between the two poles of the magnet"
    },
    {
        question: "3. Which of the following electrical devices works on the principle of electro-magnetic induction ?",
        options: ["Electric fan",
            "L.E.D",
            "Electric cooker",
            "Electric bulb"],
        correct_option: "Electric cooker"
    },
    {
        question: "4. Which costs more in the following ?",
        options: ["None",
            "Generation of DC",
            "Both costs the same",
            "Generation of AC"],
        correct_option: "Generation of DC"
    },
    {
        question: "5. Which of the following equation gives the force acting on the current carrying wire , when '\theta' be the angle between direction  of current and magnetic field ?",
        options: ["F = LIB sinθ",
            "F = ILB cosθ",
            "F = LBI sinθ",
            "F = ILB sin"],
        correct_option: "F = LIB sinθ"
    }, {
        question: "6. The polarity of electromagnet can be reversed by changing the direction of",
        options: ["Magnetic field",
            "Electric current",
            "Electric field",
            "None"],
        correct_option: "Electric current"
    },

    {
        question: "7. The ratio of magnetic force to electric force is",
        options: ["Low",
            "None",
            "Very negligible",
            "High"],
        correct_option: "Very negligible"
    },
    {
        question: "8. An induction stove works on the principle of",
        options: ["Magnetic induction",
            "Electromagnetic induction",
            "Induced EMF",
            "Electric induction"],
        correct_option: "Electromagnetic induction"
    },
    {
        question: "9. Which of the following is the product of current and EMF or voltage ?",
        options: ["Magnetic power",
            "Electric power",
            "Magnetic current",
            "Electric current"],
        correct_option: "Electric power"
    },

    {
        question: "10. Solenoid consists",
        options: ["Two slip rings",
            "Electromagnetic induction",
            "Half slip rings",
            "Soft iron core"],
        correct_option: "Soft iron core"
    },
    {
        question: "11. The current in a generator armature is AC. Because",
        options: ["The magnetic field reverses at intervals",
            "The current in the field coils in AC",
            "The rotation of the armature causes the field through into reverse",
            "The commutator feeds current into it in opposite directions every half cycl"],
        correct_option: "The rotation of the armature causes the field through into reverse"
    },
    {
        question: "12. Generally which rule is used when velocity and field are perpendicular to each other",
        options: ["Right hand rule",
            "Left hand rule",
            "Lenz's law",
            "Kirchhoff's law"],
        correct_option: "Right hand rule"
    },

    {
        question: "13. Permanent magnets are used in",
        options: ["All",
            "Speedometer",
            "Galvanometer",
            "Voltmeter"],
        correct_option: "All"
    },
    {
        question: "14. At the time of short circuit , the current in the circuit",
        options: ["Reduces substantially",
            "Does not change",
            "Increase heavily",
            "Vary continuously"],
        correct_option: "Increase heavily"
    },
    {
        question: "16. Consider the following\n" +
            "A) Magnetic flux represents the number of lines passing through the imagined plane in the field\n" +

            "B) The S.I unit of magnetic flux is weber",
        options: ["B true",
            "A and B are false",
            "A and B are true",
            "A true"],
        correct_option: "A and B are true"
    },
    {
        question: "17. The magnitude of induced emf in the coil of a generator is maximum, when coil turns through an angle of ......",
        options: ["90°",
            "180°",
            "270°",
            "90°   &  270°  "],
        correct_option: "90°"
    },
    {
        question: "18. A horse shoe magnets two poles are kept on both sides to a current carrying conductor . In this experiment the direction of force is observed as",
        options: ["The wire deflects according to right hand thumb's rule",
            "No deflection in the current wire",
            "Current wire deflects towards the south pole of magnet",
            "Current wire deflects towards the north pole of magnet"],
        correct_option: "The wire deflects according to right hand thumb's rule"
    },
    {
        question: "20. The current which changes direction after equal intervals of time is known as",
        options: ["Magnetic current",
            "Induced current",
            "DC",
            "AC"],
        correct_option: "AC"
    },

    {
        question: "21. A magnet is placed vertically on a paper. Then the number of neutral points obtained on the paper is",
        options: ["0",
            "3",
            "1",
            "2"],
        correct_option: "1"
    },
    {
        question: "22. The force applied by a remote controller on a TV is",
        options: ["Frictional",
            "Field",
            "Magnetic",
            "Electrical"],
        correct_option: "Field"
    },
    {
        question: "23. Which of the following is defined as the magnetic flux passing through unit area taken perpendicular to the field ?",
        options: ["Magnetic flux density",
            "Magnetism",
            "Magnetic flux",
            "Magnetic field"],
        correct_option: "Magnetic flux density"
    },
    {
        question: "24. When there is an angle between direction of field and velocity , the magnetic force experienced by the change is given by",
        options: ["q = FvB cosθ",
            "F = qvB cosθ",
            "B = qvf sinθ",
            "F = qvB sinθ"],
        correct_option: "F = qvB sinθ"
    }
]